## **GAVIN E. ANTHONY**

(347) 352-7152

gavinanthony1@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior Budget Analyst and Military Veteran with a Secret Security Clearance offering over 14 years of proven leadership experience in the United States Marine Corps and United States Army. Accomplished top-rated results while leading teams from four to 300 soldiers in a dynamic, fast-paced environment. Possess a comprehensive background in finance, logistics, risk management and critical thinking derived from conducting domestic operations in four states and global operations in Germany, Iraq, Qatar, Kuwait and Kurdistan. Managed risk upon multiple lines to protect property and equipment valued over \$300K and managed funds valued over \$6M daily while meeting the expectations of senior management with zero losses. Possess extensive knowledge of Military Finance Systems, budget analysis and experience in public speaking. Career is supported by extensive operational experience while in the Military and obtained a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science at the University of Mary Hardin Baylor.

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Budget Analysis
- Data Analysis
- Appropriated Funds
- Programming
- Game Development

- Finance Operations
- Problem Solving
- Risk Management
- Software Development
- Unity 3D

- Logistics
- Federal Accounting
- Project Management
- Web Development
- Visual Studio

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Texas Health and Human Services Commission Budget Analyst III

Serves as a Budget Analyst III for the Texas Health & Human Services Commission, Emergency Services, Disaster Case Management.

- Responsible for a budget in excess of \$40 million. Ensure Vendors bill state for expenditures that are in accordance with Federal, State and contractual requirements.
- Review, analyze, and adjust, monthly invoice submissions from multiple vendors contracted with the state
- Make recommendations on budget matters to higher level staff and assist in the implementation and monitoring of changes.
- Provides subject matter expertise in specific areas of budgeting, including contracts, payments, employee travel, purchasing and methods of finance verification.
- Analyze monthly operating budget reports to ensure appropriateness of allocated funds and expenditures

# University of Mary Hardin Baylor. Belton, TX Student

2013-2017

Computer Science student, proficient in the following languages C#, C++, JavaScript, PHP, CSS, MySQL and HTML5 and have also worked in the .NET environment.

U.S Army, FT. Hood, TX Budget Analyst 2012-2013

Served as a Budget Analyst for the Carl R. Darnall Medical Facility for government travel accounts and financial systems.

- Gathered, assembled, and formatted data and prepared preliminary analysis for budget preparation; assisted in the preparation and presentation of preliminary and final budget documents; prepared budget presentation materials.
- Reviewed, analyzed, and recommended to management organizational policy and procedures for department operations; participated in the development of new or revised programs, systems, procedures, and methods of operations
- Made recommendations on budget matters to higher level staff, and assisted in the implementation and monitoring of changes.

# U.S. Army, Bamberg, Germany

2010 - 2012

### **Resource Management Supervisor**

Served as Senior Manager for government travel accounts and finance systems supporting an Army unit consisting of 3K soldiers across Europe.

- Senior Manager of Defense Travel Systems and Military Pay Accounts of four separate organizations consisting of over 3K soldiers and civilians
- Served as Supervisor for 32 employees; managed review and submission of travel vouchers, pay inquiries and finance reports to brief the senior manager
- Account, manage, operate and protect property / equipment valued at \$150K+ and assets valued at \$10.5M over a two-year period with zero losses or deficiencies
- Administer and utilize various financial systems; General Funds Enterprise Business Systems (GFEBS), Defense Travel System (DTS), Organizational Defense Travel Administrator (ODTA)
- Analyzed systemic issues to provide advice and guidance on operations or other related fiscal matters to unit command leadership
- Utilized superior analytical skills successfully providing quarterly training on Government travel card policies and procedures; resulting in the reduction of delinquency program from a standard of 2% to less than 1%
- Reviewed accuracy of data processed in local automated financial sub-systems prior to interface of data in standard Army systems

Financial Manager 2007-2009

Served as Finance Manager supporting soldiers at Fort Hood; provided support to all financial and accounting operations in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom.

- Maintained disbursing files and prepared periodic financial reports; received, reviewed, prepared and computed travel youchers
- Verified accuracy of disbursing reports, travel vouchers, vendor payments and pay documents.
- Provided technical guidance to lower grade personal in the accomplishment of those duties
- Certified accuracy of accounting, budget, travel, pay, disbursing and vendor pay documents.
- Performed internal control inspections in compliance with government regulations.
- Supervised financial management operations.

GAVIN ANTHONY PAGE TWO

- Received, reviewed, and processed pay documents contracts, invoices and received reports to perform audits and analysis for unit commanders
- Deployed in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom to support combat operations while working in an austere, hostile environment to deliver funds and account for assets
- Prepared payment vouchers in accordance with various government regulations and performed duties as cashier

Served as Financial Management Analyst; overseeing the Marine Forces Reserve Commands and Marine Forces Pacific Commands in Louisiana and Camp Smith, Hawaii.

- Performed compilation of financial data and estimates for budget formulation; analysis of variances between the budget plan, budget execution, budget analysis and oversight duties
- Supervised and managed eight Marines and a budget exceeding \$5M for the Marine Corps Reserve Command
- Trained 10 unit commanders with guidance on fiscal year end close out responsibilities, proper reconciliation procedures and record keeping
- Utilized Superior analytical skills the inspection of various military command records which resulted in a 99% financial accuracy rate.

## **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS / TRAINING**

B.S, Computer Science,
Certified Texas Contract Manager
Certificate, Fiscal Law. U.S. Army, Bamberg, Germany
Certificate, Resource Management Budget Course, U.S. Army, Bamberg, DE
Certificate, Resource Management Tactical Course, U.S Army, Bamberg, DE
Certificate, General Funds Enterprise Budget System (GFEBS) Course, U.S. Army, Bamberg, DE
Certificate, Defense Travel Management Office Travel card program and policies (DTMO) Course
Certificate, Defense Travel Management Office ODTA Course

### **AWARDS**

Combat Action Medal
Army Commendation Medal
Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal
Army Achievement Medal
Iraq Campaign Medal
Global War on Terrorism